Guide to the Administrative Papers of Chancellor George Bugliarello RG.007
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
- Series III: Publications and Manuscripts
  - Subseries A: Publications and Reports (#3-#326, M, N)
    - #161 - Bugliarello, G., "Engineers--The Essential Ingredient of the Metropolitan Region," Guest Editorial, Met Section News, American Society of Mechanical Engineers, Vol. 34, No. 4, April 1984., 1984 April (Box 29, Folder 37)
    - #162 - Bugliarello, G., "Health-Care Costs: Technology to the Rescue?," IEEE Spectrum, June, 1984, pp. 97-100., 1984 June (Box 29, Folder 38)
    - #163 - Bugliarello, G., "Cronache dagli Stati Uniti: Rapporti fra universita e industria" (Chronicle from the U.S.: Relations Between University and Industry), Economia Pubblica, Vol. 1-2, 1984, pp. 56-58. (Box 29, Folder 39)
    - #164 - Bugliarello, G., "A Global Network Emerges: It Will Lead to 'Hyperintelligence,'" Science Digest, March 1984., 1984 March (Box 29, Folder 40)
    - #165 - Bugliarello, G., "Graduate Education in the Soviet Union," Proceedings, 1984 ASEE Annual Conference, Vol. II, (Lawrence P. Grayson, ed.), (1984) p.937. (Box 29, Folder 41)
    - #166 - Bugliarello, G., "Microcomputers and Engineering Education," Proceedings, 1984 ASEE Annual Conference, Vol. III, (Lawrence P. Grayson, ed.), (1984) pp. 1179-1180. (Box 29, Folder 42)
    - #167 - Bugliarello, G., "Hyperintelligence," The Futurist (December 1984) pp. 6-11., 1984 December (Box 29, Folder 43)
    - #168 - Bugliarello, G., "What Limitations on Professorial Relations with Industry?," Presented at the AAAS Annual Meeting, New York, (May 28, 1984) also appears as abstract in Resources in Education, April 1985, and in ERIC microfiche collection., 1984 May (Box 29, Folder 44)
    - #169 - Bugliarello, G., "Civil Engineering, Wake Up to the Challenge!" (Guest Editorial), ASEE Division Newsletter, (November, 1984) pp. 2-4., 1984 November (Box 29, Folder 45)
    - #170 - Bugliarello, G., "Viewpoint: The State of Engineering Education: Foundation for the Future?", Designfax, (January, 1985) pp. 27-28., 1985 January (Box 29, Folder 46)
    - #171 - Bugliarello, G., "The Ups and Downs of Civil Engineering", The Transit of Chi Epsilon, (Fall 1984), Vol. 56, No. 2, pp. 12-16., 1984 Fall (Box 29, Folder 47)
    - #172 - Bugliarello, G., "Technology and Economic Development", Metroeconomica, Vol XXXVI, No. 1, (February 1984), pp. 111-119., 1984 February (Box 29, Folder 48)
    - #173 - Bugliarello, G., "Educational Standards and the Technological University", Education on Trial, William Johnston, Ed., San Francisco: Institute for Contemporary Studies, 1985, pp. 247-253. (Box 29, Folder 49)
    - #174 - Bugliarello, G., "Water Resources Education for the Third World," Introduction, Idro Tecnica, Vol. 6, November-December 1985, pp. 373-380., 1985 December (Box 29, Folder 50)
    - #175 - Bugliarello, G. and G. Schillinger, "Editors' Note," in "Technology and Philosophy," C. Mitcham, guest ed., (Special Series) in Technology In Society, Vol. 6, p. 187 (1984). (Box 29, Folder 51)
    - #176 - Bugliarello, G. and D. J. Hockney, "A New Liberal Arts Curriculum for the Age of Technology," The Bent of Tau Beta Pi, Fall '85, pp. 50- 52., 1985 (Box 29, Folder 52)
    - #177 - Bugliarello, G. (co-author), "Reviews of National Science Policy, Greece," Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, Paris, 1984. (Box 29, Folder 53)
    - #178 - Bugliarello, G. (co-author), "Politiques Nationales de la Science et de LaTechnologie, Portugal," Paris, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 54)
    - #179 - Bugliarello, G., "The Strategic Defense Initiative and the University," Partnership With Industry And Community, ASEE 1986 Conference Proceedings. (Box 29, Folder 55)
    - #180 - Bugliarello, G., "Socio-Technology, A Quest for a New Discipline," Science, Technology & Society, Number 53, April 1986, pp. 2-5., 1986 April (Box 29, Folder 56)
    - #181 - Bugliarello, G., "Human Resources and Future Choices for Civil Engineering," ASCE Conference on Civil Engineering Education Proceedings, The Ohio State University, April 11, 1985, pp. 14-40., 1985 April (Box 29, Folder 57)
    - #182 - Bugliarello, G., "Colleges and Universities Versus Schools: Shall the Twins Meet?" National Technology Literacy Conference, Baltimore, February 16, 1986., 1986 February (Box 29, Folder 58)
    - #183 - Bugliarello, G., "Why American Industry Suffers," Management Review, September 1986, pp. 61 and 63., 1986 September (Box 29, Folder 59)
    - #184 - Bugliarello, G., "Computers and Water Resources Education: A Projection," in Journal of Water Resources Planning and Management, Vol. 113, No. 4, July 1987, pp. 498-511., 1987 July (Box 29, Folder 60)
    - #185 - Bugliarello, G. and G. Schillinger, "Editor's Note," in "Science, Technology & Individual Responsibility," D. Hart, guest ed. (Special Issue), in Technology In Society, Vol. 8, p. 237 (1986). (Box 29, Folder 61)
    - #186 - Bugliarello, G., Discussion of "Il Futuro dell'Ingegneria Italiana" ("The Future of Italian Engineering") in OICE Collana "Studi e Convegni, Vol. 14 (Rome, July 1986), pp. 85-86., 1986 July (Box 29, Folder 62)
    - #187 - Bugliarello, G., "Socio-Technology and Systems Analysis and Engineering," in Systems Science and Engineering in Water Management, Proceedings of an International Symposium in Rome, November 20-22, 1984, Accademia Nazionale dei Lincei (Rome, 1986), pp. 31-62. (Box 29, Folder 63)
    - #188 - Bugliarello, G., "Key to Technological Survival: Efficiency in Manufacturing & Product Realization," in 1987 ASEE Annual Conference Proceedings, Engineering Focuses on Excellence, p. 1886. (Box 29, Folder 64)
    - #189 - Bugliarello, G., "Technology Literacy - The Essential Task" (Opening remarks at the Second National Technology Literacy Conference, Washington, DC, February 6, 1987), Bulletin of Science, Technology & Society, Vol. 7, Nos. 1 & 2, 1987, pp. 1-2., 1987 February (Box 29, Folder 65)
    - #190 - Bugliarello, G., "Toward Hyperintelligence: Development of a Global Network of Education, Information & Cooperation", in XVI Pacific Science Conference Proceedings (Seoul, 1987), pp. 164-174. (Box 29, Folder 66)
    - #191 - Bugliarello, G., "Our Faltering Flight: The Crisis in U.S. Engineering Schools", Higher Education & National Affairs, Vol. 37, No. 2 (February 15, 1988), p.7., 1988 February (Box 29, Folder 67)
    - #192 - Bugliarello, G., "L'Importanza Delle Universita Americane Come Fonti Della Innovazione Tecnologica" ("The Importance of American Universities as Sources of Technological Innovation"), Meeting: Scienza Tecnologia E Innovazione Industriale L'Uomo e La Cultura Del 2000, No. 22-12, Nov. - Dec. 1987, pp. 46-47, 49., 1987 November-December (Box 29, Folder 68)
    - #193 - Bugliarello, G., "Why Study Science and Engineering at a Private College?" Private Colleges and Universities: Science and Engineering Edition, 1989, pp. 18-20. (Box 29, Folder 69)
    - #194 - Bugliarello, G., "New York City: Global Information Center," OBD News, Vol. II, No. 3, Spring/Summer 1988, pp. 3-4. (Box 29, Folder 70)
    - #195 - Bugliarello, G., "Six-Figure Salaries For Engineering Professors," in 1988 ASEE Annual Conference Proceedings, Beginning a New Era in Engineering Education, pp. 506-508. (Box 29, Folder 71)
    - #196 - Bugliarello, G., "Education for the Changing Pace of Technology: The Need to Transcend Our Self-Imposed Boundaries," (presentation at the 1988 winter annual meeting of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers, Chicago) in Education for the Changing Pace of Technology, ed. T.P. Torda, ASME (New York, 1988), pp. 5-7. (Box 29, Folder 72)
    - #197 - Bugliarello, G., "Fluid Mechanics in Civil Engineering: The Crisis & the Opportunity," Civil Engineering, Vol. 58, No. 12, December 1988, p. 6., 1988 December (Box 29, Folder 73)
    - #198 - Bugliarello, G., "Toward Hyperintelligence," Knowledge: Creation, Diffusion, Utilization, Vol. 10, No. l, September 1988, pp. 67-89., 1988 September (Box 29, Folder 74)
    - #199 - Bugliarello, G., "The Science - Technology - Society Matrix," Bulletin of Science, Technology & Society, Vol. 8, 1988, pp. 125-127. (Box 29, Folder 75)
    - #200 - Bugliarello, G., "Technology and the Environment," Changing the Global Environment, ed. Botkin, Caswell, Estes, Orio, Academic Press, Inc., 1989, pp. 383-402. (Box 29, Folder 76)
    - #201 - Bugliarello, G., "Some Random Thoughts on STS," NASTS NEWS, Vol 2, No. 2, April 1989, pp. 1-2., 1989 April (Box 29, Folder 77)
    - #202 - Bugliarello, G., "Youth in Engineering and Sciences Program (YES)," Education Partnerships for Work in the 21st Century: From Pilot to Policy, March 1989, pp. 17-18., 1989 March (Box 29, Folder 78)
    - #203 - Bugliarello, G., "Bioengineering: Merging the Artifact and its Maker," Mechanical Engineering, Vol. 111, No. 9, September 1989, pp. 46-48., 1989 September (Box 29, Folder 79)
    - #204 - Bugliarello, G., "Industrial Engineering - A Crucial Profession," IEEE Newsletter, Polytechnic University Student Chapter # 846, February 1989., 1989 February (Box 29, Folder 80)
    - #205 - Bugliarello, G., "Hydraulic Engineering: Global Challenge," Journal of Hydraulic Engineering, Vol. 115, No. 7, July 1989, pp. 863-868., 1989 July (Box 29, Folder 81)
    - #206 - Bugliarello, G., Science & Technology in New York City for the 21st Century: A Report by the Mayor's Commission for Science & Technology, Polytechnic Press, December 1989., 1989 December (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - #207 - Bugliarello, G., "The Genetic and Psychological Basis of Warfare as a Challenge to Scientific Research," Ethical Issues Associated with Scientific and Technological Research for the Military, ed. C. Mitcham and P. Siekevitz, Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences Vol. 577, 1989, pp. xv-xvi. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - #208 - Bugliarello, G. and A.G. Schillinger, Preface to "An International Dialogue on Science, Technology, and Society Education" in Technology In Society, vol. 11, no. 4 (1989), pp. 403-4. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - #209 - Bugliarello, G., "Un Tentativo di Sintesi" (An Attempt at Synthesizing), in Nuova Civilta delle Macchine, VII, 4 (28) (1989), pp. 44-48. (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - #210 - Bugliarello, G., "Developing A High Tech Presence," in 1990: A New Decade -- A New Administration, Proceedings of the 23rd Annual One-Day Institute - New York City Council on Economic Education at Baruch College, New York, May, 1990. (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - #211 - Bugliarello, G., "Hyperintelligence: Humankind's Next Evolutionary Step," in Rethinking the Curriculum Toward an Integrated, Interdisciplinary College Education, M.E. Clark and S.A. Wawrytko, eds., Greenwood Press, New York (1990), pp. 25-37. (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - #212 - Bugliarello, G., "Empowering Citizens Through Technology Literacy," Bulletin of Science, Technology & Society, Vol. 10, 1990, pp. 187-190. (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - #213 - Bugliarello, G., "Modeling: From Primitive Brains to Hyperintelligence," Mathematical Computer Modeling, Vol 14, 1990, pp. 1-3. (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - #214 - Bugliarello, G., "Engineering and Its Social Function: A Current Assessment," in Engineering as a Social Enterprise, presentation at the 26th Annual Meeting Symposium of the National Academy of Engineering, NAE, 1990. (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - #215 - Bugliarello, G., "Technology and the City." Symposium on the Mega-City and Mankind's Future: Population Growth and Policy Responses, United Nations University, Tokyo, 1990. (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - #216 - Bugliarello, G., "The University - and Particularly the Technological University: Pragmatism and Beyond." In The Changing University. D. Zinberg, ed. Kluwer Academic Publishers, The Netherlands, 1991. (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - #217 - Bugliarello, G., "New Trends in Resource Management," in New Trends on the Resource Management, Proceedings of the First Pacific Rim Conference on the Resource Management. National Chiao Tung University, Hsinchu, Taiwan. April 17-19, 1991, pp. 1-21., 1991 April (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - #218 - Bugliarello, G., "Philosophy of Technology, or the Quest for a 'Hominis ad Hominim ad Machinam Proportio.'" Stephen H. Cutcliffe, Steven L. Goldman, Manuel Medina and Jose Sanmartin, eds. New Worlds, New Technologies, New Ideas. Lehigh University Press, 1991. (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - #219 - Bugliarello, G., "Metrotech as a Model of Economic and Community Development." Fostering a Technologically Adaptable Workforce. Proceedings of the New York State Legislative Commission on Science and Technology, Report No. 92-1. Albany, February 1992., 1992 February (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - #220 - Bugliarello, G., "The Future of Science." Speech presented at the ARCS Scholarship Awards Luncheon, New York, NY. Polytechnic Press, May 1991., 1991 May (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - #221 - Bugliarello, G., "L'Acqua: Prospettive per l'Anno 2000." (Water: Perspective for the Year 2000). (Summary) Scienze e Tecnica, Vol. 54, nn. 253-254, Sept.-Oct. 1991, pp. 7-8., 1991 September-October (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - #222 - Bugliarello, G., "Broad Issues in Science, Technology & Society." Technological Literacy Workshop Proceedings. Russel C. Jones, ed. National Science Foundation, Association of American Colleges, Accreditation Board for Engineering & Technology, 1991. (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - #223 - Bugliarello, G., "How Long Will We Continue to Accept the Dismantling of Our Industry?" Keynote speech presented at the 1991 American Electronics Association University-Industry Conference, San Diego, CA. Polytechnic Press, Jan. 1992., 1992 January (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - #224 - Bugliarello, G., "The Educational System and New York," Metropolitan New York Business and Market Guide, New York Board of Trade. New York, NY, 1992. (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - #227 - Bugliarello, G., "The Ideal of Civil Engineering," Journal of Professional Issues in Engineering Education and Practice, Vol. 120, No. 3, ASCE, July, 1994., 1994 July (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - #228 - Bugliarello, G., "Restructuring Engineering Education: Disciplinary vs. Interdisciplinary." Conference proceedings at the Illinois Institute of Technology's New Challenges in Educating Engineers. June 10-11, 1991., 1991 June (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - #229 - Bugliarello, G., "Science at the Crossroads," Ethics, Values, and the Promise of Science, The Sigma Xi, 1993. (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - #230 - Bugliarello, G., "The Future of Bioengineering," Medical & Biological Engineering in the Future of Health Care, J.D. Andrade, ed., Utah University Press, 1994. (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - #231 - Bugliarello, G., "Technology Transfer: A Socio-Technological Paradigm," in Development and Transfer of Industrial Technology, O.C.C. Lin, C.T. Shih and J.C. Yang (eds.) Elsevier Science B.V., 1994 ITRI. (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - #232 - Bugliarello, G., "Metrotech: An Urban, University-Industry Park," The Journal of Urban Technology, R.E. Hanley, ed., New York City Technical College, Vol. 1, No. 2, Spring 1993, pp. 41-48., 1993 Spring (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - #233 - Bugliarello, G., "The Role of the University in Charting a Path for the Twenty-first Century," Presentation to American Chemical Society's New York Section Symposium Catalyst for Change, Oct. 1993., 1993 October (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - #234 - Bugliarello, G., "Science at the Crossroads," in Cosmic Beginnings and Human Ends, C.N. Matthews and R.A. Varghese, eds., Open Court, Chicago and La Salle, 1995. (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - #235 - Bugliarello, G., "The Future of Engineering Education," Presentation to the 1994 International Mechanical Engineering Congress & Exhibition, of the Winter Annual Meeting, Chicago, IL, Nov. 6-11, 1994., 1994 November (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - #236 - Bugliarello, G., "The Future of Bioengineering," in Medical and Biological Engineering in the Future of Health Care, J.D. Andrade, ed., University of Utah Press, Salt Lake City, 1994. (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - #237 - Bugliarello, G., "The Global Generation, Transmission, and Diffusion of Knowledge: How Can the Developing Countries Benefit?," in Marshaling Technology for Development, Proceedings of a Symposium, National Research Council and The World Bank, National Academy Press, Washington, DC, 1995. (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - #239 - Bugliarello, G., "Generazione e Diffusione delle Informazioni: Necessità dei Paesi in Via di Sviluppo," Energia e Materie Prime, N. 102, February 1995, pp. 20-31., 1995 February (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - #240 - Bugliarello, G., "The Bioengineer and the Future," CHEMTECH, Vol. 25, No. 3, March 1995, pp. 12-14., 1995 March (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - #241 - Bugliarello, G., A.A. Martinez, G. Sirilli and G. Rufo, Examiners' Report in Reviews of National Science and Technology Policy - Turkey, OECD, Paris, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 33)
    - #242 - Bugliarello, G., "Engineering," in Encyclopedia of the Future, G.T. Kurian and G.T.T. Molitor, eds., Simon & Schuster Macmillan, New York, 1996, Vol. I, pp. 238-240. (Box 30, Folder 34)
    - #243 - Bugliarello, G., "Telecommunications, Politics, Economics, and National Sovereignty: A New Game," Airpower Journal, Vol. X, No. 1, Spring 1996, pp. 6-17., 1996 Spring (Box 30, Folder 35)
    - #244 - Bugliarello, G., "Engineering in Services," American Society for Engineering Education Annual Meeting, June 1996, ASEE, World Wide Web 1996 (Box 30, Folder 36)
    - #245 - Bugliarello, G., "Urban Knowledge Parks and Economic and Social Development Strategies," Journal of Urban Planning and Development, June 1996, ASCE, New York, pp. 33-45., 1996 June (Box 30, Folder 37)
    - #245a - Bugliarello, G., "R&D in the U.S. Today: A Difficult Moment and New Needs," Energy and Environmental Policy in a Period of Transition, Proceedings of the Twenty-third Annual Illinois Energy Conference, University of Illinois at Chicago, 1996. (Box 30, Folder 38)
    - #246 - Bugliarello, G., "Technological Literacy," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol. 27, No. 1, Spring 1997., 1997 Spring (Box 30, Folder 39)
    - #247 - Bugliarello, G., "Bioengineering Ethics: the Ethics of the Linkage Between Engineering and Biology," Keynote speech presented at the First International Conference on Ethical Issues in Biomedical Engineering at Clemson University. September 29, 1997., 1997 September (Box 30, Folder 40)
    - #248 - Bugliarello, G., "Telecommunities: The Next Civilization," The Futurist, September/October 1997, pp. 23-26., 1997 September-October (Box 30, Folder 41)
    - #249 - Bugliarello, G., "Biomimesis: The Road Less Traveled," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol 27, No.3, Fall 1997, 1997 Fall (Box 30, Folder 42)
    - #249a. Bugliarello, G., "Urban Knowledge Parks; The Example of Metrotech in New York City," in Science Parks, Innovation and High Technologies: Ways for Growth, Competitiveness and Internationalization of Economy, Proceedings of the XIV IASP (International Association of Science Parks) World Conference on Science and Technology Parks, AREA Science Parks, Trieste, 1997. (Box 30, Folder 43)
    - #249b - Bugliarello, G., "Challenge in Distribution of Knowledge," Les Nouvelles, Journal of the Licensing Executives Society, Volume XXXII, No. 1, March 1997., 1997 March (Box 30, Folder 44)
    - #249c - Bugliarello, G., "Telecomunicações, Telecomunidades e Soberania Nacional," VI Congresso das Comunicações, Ediçãi da Assicuação Portuguesa para o Desenvilvimento das Comunicações, Lisbon, 1997. (Box 30, Folder 45)
    - #250 - Bugliarello, G., "Engineering and the Crossroads of Our Species," The Bridge, Vol 28, No. 1, Spring 1998. National Academy of Engineering., 1998 Spring (Box 30, Folder 46)
    - #251 - Bugliarello, G., "Biology, Society and Machines," American Scientist, Vol 86, May-June 1998., 1998 May-June (Box 30, Folder 47)
    - #252 - Bugliarello, G., "An Engineering Response to Terrorism," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol. 28, No. 3, Fall 1998., 1998 Fall (Box 30, Folder 48)
    - #253 - Bugliarello, G."S&T As An Element in Developing A Global Market," Globalization of Science and Technology: A Way for C.I.S. Countries to New Markets, Kluwer Academic Publishers, Netherlands, 1998, pp. 9-13. (Box 30, Folder 49)
    - #254- Bugliarello, G., "Some Thoughts on Knowledge as the New Societal Leit Motiv and How It Affects Colleges and Universities," in International Cooperation in Science and Technology, 1998 Sigma Xi Forum Proceedings, The Sigma Xi, Research Triangle Park, 1999. (Box 30, Folder 50)
    - #255 - Bugliarello, G., "Knowledge Parks and Incubators," Technology Management Handbook, CRC Press, 1999, pp. 1-41. (Box 30, Folder 51)
    - #256 - Bugliarello, G., "The City as an Adaptive Entity," Journal of Urban Technology, Vol. 6, Number 2, pp. 1-11, the Society of Urban Technology, 1999. (Box 30, Folder 52)
    - #257 – Bugliarello, G. and A.G. Schillinger, Editorial Acknowledgment, Technology In Society, Vol. 21, 1999, pp. 345-347. (Box 30, Folder 53)
    - #258 - Bugliarello, G., "Engineering and the Crossroads of Our Species," Humankind Advancing, Vol. 10, No. 2, April 1999., 1999 April (Box 30, Folder 54)
    - #259 - Bugliarello, G., "There's Work to Be Done," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol. 29, No. 3, Fall 1999., 1999 Fall (Box 30, Folder 55)
    - #260 - Bugliarello, G., "Megacities and the Developing World," The Bridge, Vol. 29, No. 4, Winter 1999., 1999 Winter (Box 30, Folder 56)
    - #261 - Bugliarello, G., "The Interdisciplinarity Imperative: To Create New Knowledge and Uses of Knowledge Across Boundaries of Disciplines and Institutions," in The Interdisciplinary Imperative: Interactive Research and Education Still an Elusive Goal in Academia, Rustum Roy (ed.), Writers Club Press, San Jose, 2000. (Box 30, Folder 57)
    - #262 - Bugliarello, G., "Reflections on Technological Literacy," Bulletin of Science, Technology & Society, Vol. 20, No. 2, April 2000, pp. 83-89., 2000 April (Box 30, Folder 58)
    - #263 - Bugliarello, G., "Balance!," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol. 30, No. 1, Spring 2000, 2000 Spring (Box 30, Folder 59)
    - #264 - Bugliarello, G., "Rethinking Urbanization," Engineering and Environmental Challenges, October 24, 2000, 2000 October (Box 30, Folder 60)
    - #265 - Bugliarello, G., "The Biosoma: The Synthesis of Biology, Machines and Society," Bulletin of Science, Technology & Society, Vol. 20, No. 6, December 2000, pp. 452-464, 2000 December (Box 30, Folder 61)
    - #266 - Bugliarello, G., "Developing Partnerships," in Tools for Better Learning - Reshaping Undergraduate Science and Engineering Education, Proceedings of the 1999 Sigma Xi Forum, Sigma Xi, The Scientific Research Society, Inc., Research Triangle Park, NC, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 62)
    - #267 - Bugliarello, G., "Rethinking Urbanization," The Bridge, Vol. 31, No. 1, Spring 2001, 2001 Spring (Box 30, Folder 63)
    - #268 - Bugliarello, G., Larry G. Lehowicz, Margaret N. Novack, "The Quest to Replace Antipersonnel Landmines," The Bridge, Vol. 31, No. 2, Summer 2001, 2001 Spring (Box 30, Folder 64)
    - #269 - Bugliarello, G., "Urban Knowledge Parks," in Frontiers of Entrepreneurship and Innovation - Readings in Science Park Policies and Practices, Formica, P. and L. Sanz (eds.), International Association of Science Parks, 2002 (Box 30, Folder 65)
    - #270 - Bugliarello, G., "Frontiers of Engineering," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol. 31, No. 4, Winter 2001., 2001 Winter (Box 30, Folder 66)
    - #271 – Bugliarello, G., "Engineering and Homeland Defense," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol. 32, No. 1, Spring 2002., 2002 Spring (Box 30, Folder 67)
    - #272 - Bugliarello, G., "Our Energy Future," Editorial, The Bridge, Vol. 32, No. 2, Summer 2002., 2002 Summer (Box 30, Folder 68)
    - #273 - Bugliarello, G., "Virtual Nations or Telecommunities," Commentary, The Futurist, July-August 2002., 2002 July-August (Box 30, Folder 69)